serverpilot.io 2019-03-03

# ServerPilot Privacy Policy - ServerPilot

Effective May 25, 2018

This Privacy Policy describes the information that ServerPilot gathers, uses, and shares in connection with your use of ServerPilot's website (serverpilot.io), services, and software (collectively, the "Services").

When we refer to "ServerPilot", "we", "us", or "our", that means FreedomCP, Inc., the company that owns and operates ServerPilot and its Affiliates. We're headquartered in the United States.

For the purposes of this Policy:

  * "Websites" refers to serverpilot.io as well as any other websites ServerPilot owns and that link to this Policy. For clarity, "Websites" does not include any sites owned or operated by our Customers.
  * "Customers" are those who register on their own or on behalf of an entity or organization to use our Services.
  * "End Users" means individuals who visit our Customers' websites.

## 1\. OUR PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

We keep your personal information personal and private. We will not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose your personal information to anyone except as necessary to provide our services or as otherwise described in this Policy without first providing you with notice and the opportunity to consent.

## 2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

**Name, Email Address, and Other Contact Information.** We collect personal information you provide us when you sign up for our Services, submit forms on our websites, and send us support or sales inquiry emails.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.** We may use cookies and other information gathering technologies for a variety of purposes, such as providing us with information about how you interact with our Services and assisting us in marketing and advertising. You may opt-out of such personalized advertising [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) if located in the United States or [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) if located in the European Union. For analytics, we use services such as Google Analytics that set their own cookies. You can read about how Google Analytics uses your data [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). Our payment processors such as Stripe set their own cookies, as well. Stripe's Privacy Policy and information about their use of data is available [here](https://stripe.com/us/privacy).

**User Content.** Our websites may offer publicly accessible forums or discussion sections. If you choose to participate in any of these areas, any information you post in the area might be read, collected, and used by others who access it. If you wish to remove your personal information from any these areas, please see Your Data Rights below.

**Log Files.** When you visit our Websites, we gather certain information and store it in log files. This information may include but is not limited to IP addresses, browser version information, and URLs of referring pages.

**Server Usage and Contents.** For servers you use with our Service or install our software on, we may collect and monitor information about the server, including hardware information, configuration information, network traffic, and file contents. We use this data for the purposes described in this Policy such as to operate, improve, and personalize the Services, provide customer support, protect the security and safety of our Customers, and develop aggregate analysis.

**Customer Account Information.** When you register for a ServerPilot account, we collect your email address. Once registered, you may provide additional information to help us identify you.

**Payment Information.** When you sign up for one of our paid Services, you must provide billing information. For example, if you pay with a credit card, we will collect your card information which we store with a third-party payment processor such as Stripe.

## 3\. LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING

Our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information depends on the personal information collected and the specific context in which we collect it. We normally will collect personal information from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so, (b) we need your personal information to perform a contract with you (e.g. to deliver the Services you have requested), or (c) the processing is in our legitimate interests. We have a legitimate interest in operating our Services and communicating with you as necessary to provide these Services, for example when responding to your queries, improving our platform, protecting the safety and security of our Services and our Customers, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities. Please note that in most cases, if you do not provide the requested information, ServerPilot will not be able to provide the requested service to you.

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you, or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

## 4\. HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

ServerPilot only processes personal information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized. We may use the information we collect (including personal information, to the extent applicable) to:

  * provide, operate, maintain, improve, personalize, and promote the Website and Services;
  * enable you to access and use the Website and Services;
  * process and complete invoice payments;
  * send transactional messages, including to provide customer support, and send you technical notices and security alerts;
  * send commercial communications, in accordance with your communication preferences, such as providing you with information about products and services;
  * monitor and analyze usage for marketing or advertising purposes;
  * comply with legal obligations as well as to investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to the Services, and other illegal activities;
  * process for other purposes for which we obtain your consent.

**Information from Third Party Services.** We may combine information we collect as described above with personal information we obtain from third parties. For example, for sales inquiries, we may combine information provided by you with information from third parties in order to better market our services to you.

## 5\. INFORMATION SHARING

We work with other companies who help us run our business ("Service Providers"). These companies provide services to help us deliver customer support, process credit card payments, provide marketing support, and otherwise operate and improve our Services. You can find a list of our sub-processors at <https://serverpilot.io/gdpr/subprocessors>.

In addition to sharing with Service Providers as described above, we may also share your information with others in the following circumstances:

  * with ServerPilot's Affiliates (other services owned and operated by FreedomCP, Inc.);
  * when we are required to disclose personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * where we have a good-faith belief sharing is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Service Agreement, or as otherwise required to comply with our legal obligations;
  * as you may otherwise consent to from time to time.

ServerPilot has potential liability for onward transfers of personal data to third parties.

We do not sell, rent, or share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

## 6\. DATA AGGREGATION

ServerPilot may aggregate data we acquire about our Customers and their End Users, including the Log Data and Server Usage and Contents described above. For example, we may assemble data to determine whether attacks are being performed against servers and applications of our Customers or their End Users, to identify common applications and application versions, to identify server and application performance profiles, or to compile information and statistics for informational or marketing purposes.

## 7\. INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION TRANSFERS

We store your information in the United States. If you are accessing or using our Websites or Services or otherwise providing information to us, you are agreeing to the transfer of your personal information to the United States. ServerPilot is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

ServerPilot complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. ServerPilot has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, ServerPilot commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact ServerPilot at:

ServerPilot  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  
P.O. Box 66  
Bellingham, WA  
98227-0066  

ServerPilot has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. Additionally, an individual may be allowed to invoke binding arbitration through a Privacy Shield Panel to resolve disputes under certain limited conditions.

## 8\. YOUR DATA RIGHTS

Regardless of country, you can always contact us if you wish to exercise your data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the following data protection rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):

  * Where we rely on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline consent at any time.
  * Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your personal data, you have the right to object.
  * You have the right to access, correct, update, export, or delete your personal information.
  * You can access, correct, update, or export your account information by editing your profile at [https://serverpilot.io](https://serverpilot.io/).
  * To delete your account information or make any other personal information requests, you can email us at [privacy@serverpilot.io](mailto:privacy@serverpilot.io).

## 9\. YOUR CHOICES

You can use some of the features of the Services without registering, thereby limiting the type of information that we collect.

You may unsubscribe from receiving certain promotional emails from us. If you wish to do so, simply follow the instructions found at the end of the email. Even if you unsubscribe, we may still contact you for informational, transactional, account-related, or similar purposes.

Many browsers have an option for disabling cookies, which may prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or enable selective use of cookies. Please note that, if you choose not to accept cookies, some features and the personalization of our Services may no longer work for you. You will continue to receive advertising material but it will not be tailored to your interests.

## 10\. COMMUNICATION PREFERENCES

You may manage your receipt of commercial communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of such emails. Even if you unsubscribe, we may still contact you for informational, transactional, account-related, or similar purposes such as to notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy or respond to support requests.

## 11\. DATA SECURITY, DATA INTEGRITY, AND ACCESS

We take all reasonable steps to protect information we receive from you from loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and/or destruction. We have put in place appropriate technical and administrative measures to safeguard and secure your information, and we make use of technologies such as encryption to increase privacy and security.

## 12\. NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES

This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on our websites. If we materially change the ways in which we use or share personal information previously collected from you through our Services, we will notify you through our Services, by email, or using other communication.

## 13\. BUSINESS TRANSACTIONS

We may assign or transfer this Policy, as well as information covered by this Policy, in the event of a merger, sale, change in control, or reorganization of all our part of our business.

## 14\. CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us by email at [privacy@serverpilot.io](mailto:privacy@serverpilot.io).
